Tavish Aggarwal

♥ Hyderabad, India
India</t

SUMMARY

Data Scientist with 5 years of extensive experience in Predictive Modeling, Computer Vision, NLP, Neural networks, and AIOps. I am seeking an opportunity to transform the company's data towards business excellence and enhance the decision–making process.

EXPERIENCE

Senior Software Engineer - Data Scientist

ACS Solutions

January 2020 - Present, Hyderabad

- · Positively impacted a client by leading the 5 members team to transform the business digitally.
- Taken responsibility for converting the business problem into a Data Science problem.
- Build a knowledge base in the team by exploring Reinforcement Learning and Deep Learning case studies leveraging a 90% increase in team productivity.

Software Engineer - Data Scientist

ACS Solutions

August 2017 - December 2019, Hyderabad

- · Honored with the "Employee of the Year" award for commitment and the mission to ensure business success.
- Developed ML models and achieved measurable results while working in the supply chain, healthcare, and e-commerce.
- · Acquired client trust by taking responsibility for major deliverables, which helped expand the team size from 4 to 12 members.

Software Engineer

MAQ Software

June 2016 - July 2017, Hyderabad

- · Delivered products using the latest technology stack such as HTML, CSS, Angular, SQL, SharePoint workflow, Java, and AWS.
- · Honoured 3 times with the "Employee of the Month" title for exceeding customer's expectations.
- $\cdot \ \, \text{Developed end-to-end solutions in an agile environment for stakeholders simplifying day-to-day counterfeit operations.}$

SKILLS

Fields of Interest: Machine Learning, NLP, Computer Vision, Neural Networks

Technical Skills: Python, Flask, Django, Keras, AWS, HTML, JavaScript, NodeJS

Language Skills: English, Hindi

INDUSTRY PROJECTS

Supply Chain: Customer Dashboard

ACS Solutions • January 2021

- · Dashboard developed in Power BI giving 360-degree insights of customer engagement and business flows.
- Dashboard helped sales representatives and improved monthly shipments by 37%.
- Dashboard includes 40+ analytical, predictive, and prescriptive KPIs giving possible suggestions about the booking capabilities, manufacturing performances, and generating alerts.

Supply Chain: Order Quality Prediction

ACS Solutions · May 2020

- Developed a data pipeline analyzing complex data flow from SAP systems into the AWS data lake efficiently. The standardization in the process improved the 100% cross-functional team efficiency.
- · Found 1 major and 2 medium priority gaps in the business process from the collected data.
- The developed order quality model helped monitor the health of the order book and bring down default orders by 20%.

Ecommerce: Login Anomaly Detection

ACS Solutions · April 2019

- · The client faced an economic loss of around 1 million dollars because of unethical users accessing the system.
- Build the unsupervised model using the PyOD package to find 1% of anomalous users and achieved hypothesis-driven 20% improved results.
- \cdot Implemented a flask solution and hosted in the lambda function, saving 60% infrastructure cost.

Healthcare Industry: Claims Data Analysis

ACS Solutions • January 2018

- \cdot Solved use case of high claim settlement time of 10 minutes for different hospitals.
- · Solved a use case to read 10,000+ EDI file data monthly using AWS lambda functions and generate a dashboard for the insurers.
- Designed a storytelling dashboard that improved settlement time duration by 80%.

EDUCATION

Masters in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence Liverpool John Moores University \cdot Liverpool, England \cdot 2021

PG Diploma in Machine Learning and Artificial Intelligence International Institute of Information Technology · Bangalore, India · 2020

Bachelor of Technology in Software Engineering SRM University · Hyderabad, India · 2016